<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>F# on naveen srinivasan</title><link>/categories/f#/</link><description>Recent content in F# on naveen srinivasan</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 22:33:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/f#/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Solution to Adventcode Day 7 in FSharp</title><link>/?p=2641/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 22:33:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/?p=2641/</guid><description>Here is my solution to adventcode problem 7 using F#.
I am using the adventofcode to improve my functional programming skills. The gist of the problem is to solve the logic gates which is represented as 16 bit integer’s and these depend on other gates.
The puzzle starts of with simple problem
123 -&amp;gt; x 456 -&amp;gt; y ``Here is my solution to adventcode problem 7 using F#. I am using the adventofcode to improve my functional programming skills.</description></item><item><title>fsharp docker image</title><link>/?p=2481/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 02:41:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>/?p=2481/</guid><description>The fsharp project has a official docker image https://github.com/fsprojects/docker-fsharp. The one issue with that is it is based on mono 4.0.4 which is buggy and fsharp does not work very well. The latest alpha release of the mono with which fsharp works well is 4.2.0. The 4.2.0 isn’t available in stable channels.
So I created a docker image with the latest mono from their alpha repo and using the latest fsharp from the github.</description></item><item><title>Using F# to Automate Reading–The Morning Brew</title><link>/?p=997/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2010 04:27:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/?p=997/</guid><description>I guess most of the .NET Devs read The Morning Brew, if not you should. It is a morning newspaper for the dev, so I end up reading it first thing when I go to work. I like to try and automate most of the stuff . So I thought why not write a script that reads the Morning Brew feed, filter the excluded content that I am not interested in and open the urls before I come in.</description></item><item><title>Resharper Template for F#</title><link>/?p=6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2010 19:06:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>/?p=6/</guid><description>I have been hacking F# lately and I am big fan of ReSharper. So why not create a few Live Templates for the things i do daily in F#.
Download R# live template for F#. I am sure there are few more things that can be part of this template. I have posted the code in MSDN Code gallery so that others can find and contribute.</description></item></channel></rss>